### Brendan MacDonald

Address: 98 Long Crook, South Queensferry, EH30 9XS Tel: 07593 710 566

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/brendan-macdonald Email: macbrendan@gmail.com

#### **Summary**

I am an ISEB-certified Senior Tester with over 15 years experience in software quality assurance. I have spent the past few years improving my manual, automation, and performance testing skills on agile projects. I am really keen to improve my testing skills further and work towards becoming a technically strong software tester.

### Technical Skills

Automation Tools	Selenium Webdriver WebdriverIO Behat
Performance Tools	JMeter Gatling K6
Devops Tools	Circle CI Jenkins CI
Defect Tracking	JIRA HP Quality Center
Source Control	GitHub Bitbucket
Languages	Java Javascript

## Professional Experience

Jun 2017 - Present Scott Logic

Edinburgh, UK

**Senior Tester** working for a cross-business sector consultancy. Delivered test

automation and performance testing for clients including the Royal Bank of Canada and Acuris:

- Created multiple proofs of concept:
  - using Java and Selenium to drive various browsers through UI flows controlled using JUnit
  - using Appium with Java to test web and native apps on both physical and emulated Android devices
  - using Gatling and k6 for the performance testing of a banking backend
- Native app testing on iOS devices using manual exploratory techniques
- API testing using Jest and Supertest for internal projects
- Mentoring of graduates on a variety of topics from test planning to mobile app testing
- Wrote a <u>blog series</u> on Security testing with Zap proxy

Jan 2015 - May 2017 Cameron & Wilding

London, UK

**Automation engineer** working for a Drupal agency focused on the publishing and media sector. Working on agile projects for clients like The Economist and The Telegraph, I introduced testing practices and provided test

automation along with continuous integration workflows:

- Created a PHP framework around the BDD tool Behat to provide rapid setup, and a structure and standard to the automation process
- Performed visual regression testing using BackstopJS and Java with Selenium
- Performed performance testing using JMeter and Sitespeed
- Cross mobile device and cross-browser testing using Browserstack and Saucelabs
- Put in place CI processes using Jenkins and Circle CI to incorporate the automation tests into the deployment workflows
- Introduced a Test Strategy to the company and implemented Test Plans for all of our projects
- Provided Behat training to the company and the wider public through workshops run through EventBrite
- Attended and presented at Drupal Camps in the UK

#### Apr 2013 – Dec 2014 e-testing

London, UK

**Test Consultant** working for an independent testing company. The majority of my time was spent on client site at Cancer Research working as part of an agile development team as the sole automation engineer to implement a UFT-based automation framework for their flagship product, Race For Life. I was also involved in the automation of their Drupal sites using Behat and Robot Framework:

- Designing bespoke data-driven UFT automated tests based on user stories – form filling, payment processing, database checks
- Using UFT and VB Script to create automated tests
- Using Robot Framework / Selenium2Library and Behat / Mink to automate Drupal websites
- Configuring Jenkins CI to manage and report on the automated tests

Jun 2010 – Apr 2013 Hewlett Packard

Wellington, NZ

**Automation Engineer** working as part of a 15-member Test Team on the Passport Replacement project for the Department of Internal Affairs. My role involved:

- Designing QTP automated tests based on Functional Requirements and Use Cases
- Providing estimates of test effort based on the test design
- Writing Business Process Test (BPT) components and flows in HP Quality Centre
- Converting BPT components into QTP Scripted components.
- Using QTP and VBScript to write new code for the BPT components and functions

Jun 2009 – Jun 2010 Senior Test Analyst	Westpac	Wellington, NZ
Jun 2007 – Jun 2009 Senior Test Analyst	Hewlett Packard	Wellington, NZ
Jun 2006 – Jun 2007 Test Analyst	IAG	Wellington, NZ
Dec 2004 – Jun 2006 Test Analyst	SolNet Solutions	Wellington, NZ
Sep 2002 – Oct 2004 Test Analyst	LogicaCMG	London, UK

# Education & Courses

Sep 2000 – Sep 2001 University of Aberdeen

MSc Information Technology & Intelligent Systems

Aberdeen, UK

Sep 1994 – Sep 1998 University of Aberdeen BSc Honours (2.1) Biochemistry (Immunology)

Aberdeen, UK

Dec 2005 **Equinox ISEB Foundation Certificate Exam** 

Wellington, NZ